Mss.Ms.Coll.115
American Philosophical Society
- Series II. Kane Family Legal Papers, 1824-1919; A collection of father, John Kintzing Kane, and son, Robert Patterson Kane, legal briefs, relating to numerous and varied cases in Philadelphia and Pennsylvania. There is information on the Chesapeake and Delaware Canal Company, the Delaware waterbre
  - Fitzsimmons, Thomas, 1804 May 29
    Certificate from the Delaware Insurance office.
  - Fleming vs. Page, 1849 August
  - Flommerfelt, et al vs. the ship Susan G. Owens, 1837-1849
    See: Sundry persons vs. the Susan G. Owens.
  - Ford vs. Thomas, 1835-1838
  - Foster, Ezekiel B. vs. John K. Green., 1848 May 20
  - Fowle vs. Spear, 1847 November 22
  - Fox, Margaret, 1862
  - Franklin Fire Insurance Company of Philadelphia, 1853 November 25
    Policy with Samuel M. Leiper.
  - Franklin Fire Insurance Comapny of Philadelphia, 1851 June 3
    Policy to Edward S. McGlue.
  - French Commission, 1834 May 5
    Cases examined.
  - Fricke, Henry and Thomas H. Fenton, 1845
  - Fritz vs. Northrop and Lewis, 1841
  - Furey tax papers, 1831 July 7
  - Gardner, Grace vs. William Wagner, 1829-1839
  - Garesché, Ann, 1845 November 1
    Agreement to sell home of P.S. DuPonceau.
  - Garmindia, 1845 February
    Case regarding molasses.
  - Garrett, Philip, 1842
  - Gattmann, Isaac, 1855 June 1
    Petition to commissioner of patents.
  - Germantown Bank vs. Say, 1829-1830
  - Geyelin, Emile
    Agreement with Henry J. Taylor.
  - Gibbon, James and Gabriel Duvall, 1826 November 30
    Deed to Elizabeth Coultas Leiper.
  - Girard Bank vs. American Exchange Company., 1841
  - Girard Bank vs. Burden, 1839
  - Girard Bank vs. Comly, 1837
  - Girard Bank vs. Congell, 1841
  - Girard Bank vs. Richards, et al, 1840
  - Girard Bank vs. Washington Jackson, 1841 November 15
  - Grants vs. Taylor, 1838
  - Gray vs. Gibson, 1864
  - Gray's Ferry, 1837
    Sale of estate.
  - Greig, John #1
  - Greig, John #2
  - Greig, John #3
  - Greig, John #4
  - Greig, Mr., 1845 November 13
    Estate.
  - Grubb vs. Bayard, 1850 May 2
  - Guardians vs. Taylor
  - Harmstad, E. and Company, 1840 February
    Agreement with J.K. Kane.
  - Harper, James vs. John Struthers, 1840 June 5
  - Hartman, John vs. The Brig Will, 1848 June 20
    Possession.
  - Hazelton Coal Company, 1836-1843
    An act to incorporate the Hazelton Coal Company.
  - Hazelton Coal Company, 1843
    Mortgage to Jacob Souder and Alisha Jenkins.
  - Heazlitt, Charles F., 1865 February 3
  - Hennicker vs. Hennicker, 1790 May 21
  - Herr, Daniel vs. Edward Stacey, 1850-1852
  - Hess, Simon J., 1856 May 13
    Deed to A.J. Wilcox
  - Hill vs. Peterson, 1847 January 22
  - Hitner vs. the Napoleon, 1855 April 19
  - Hitner, Reeves and Company vs. the Enterprize, 1851
  - Hopkins, John vs. David R. Porter, 1852 April 19
  - Hutchinson, Randal, 1831 July 21
    Assignment of mortgage and debt to Thomas B. Prichett.
  - Indigent Widow's Society, 1845 May 12
    Regarding Stewart's legacy.
  - Ingersoll, C.J. vs. Naylor, 1832-1846
  - Jackson, Washington, 1829 June 22
    Bond to R. Hutchinson.
  - Jackson, Washington, 1831 July 31
    Mortgage to R. Hutchinson.
  - Jackson, Washington, 1829 June 20
    Mortgage to Samuel Smith.
  - James vs. Thomas, Undated
  - Janeway, J.J., 1830 November 4
    Deed to J.K. Kane.
  - Janeway, T.D., 1845 November 21
  - Jenks, W. D., Undated
  - Jenks, W.P., 1845 October
    Recommendation.
  - Jeppeson vs. the Aurora, 1849 May 12
  - John and Joseph (ship) vs. Le Courrier de la Manche (ship), 1806
  - Jones, Charles Thomson vs. Joseph M. Thomas, 1847
  - Jones, et al, vs. American Mutual Insurance Company., 1852 October
  - Juniper vs. Lyra., 1848
  - Kane, C. V. S. vs. Morris Canal and Banking Company., 1836-1838
  - Kane, Elizabeth F., 1919
    Income.
  - Kane, E.K., 1845, 1858
    Farmers & Merchants Bank cancelled checks.
  - Kane, Elizabeth K., 1854
  - Kane, J.K., 1854
    Account with McKean & Elk Land...Co
  - Kane, J.K., 1852-1855
    Bills...
  - Kane, J.K., 1834 December 15
    Bond to John Constable
  - Kane, J.K., Undated
    Confessions.
  - Kane, J.K., 1855-1858
  - Kane, J.K., 1854
    Estate, in Account with Child & Patterson.
  - Kane, J.K., 1858
    Estate, Monies to Miss Kane.
  - Kane, J.K., 1858
    Estate, Receipts with R.P.Kane.
  - Kane, J.K., 1859
    Estate, Receipts with R.P. Kane.
  - Kane, J.K., 1851
    Fugitive Nancy, Perdue's slave.
  - Kane, J.K., 1824-1830
    Insurance policies.
  - Kane, J.K., 1849
    Lease to Steinmetz.
  - Kane, J.K., 1851 March 25
    Lease to William Wilent.
  - Kane, J.K., 1853
    Mortgage to R. Willing.
  - Kane, J.K., 1837
    Pew certificates with 2nd Presbyterian Church.
  - Kane, J.K., Undated
    Notes on Question of Pardons.
  - Kane, J.K., 1829 September 5
    B.W. Richards.
  - Kane, J.K., 1857-1858
    Settlement with Mutual Assurance Co.
  - Kane, J.K., 1848 October 25
    Survey of Market Street Properties.
  - Kane, J.K., Undated
    Views...
  - Kane, J.K. deceased, 1858 March 10
  - Kane, R.P., Undated
    Argument for Williamson.
  - Kane, R.P., 1858 March 4
    Settlement with Childs & Peterson.
  - Kane, R.P., Mrs., 1890
  - Kane, Robert P., 1852
  - Kane, T.L., 1858
    Banking Material.
  - Kane, T.L., 1854
    Bond to J.K. Kane.
  - Kane, T.L., 1860 February 2
    Declaration of Trust.
  - Kane, T.L., 1853 January
    Power of Attorney to J.K. Kane.
  - Kane, T.L., 1858
    R.P. Kane.
  - Kane, T.L., 1860 February 22
    Settlement of Account with E.K. Kane's Estate.
  - Keim and Haines vs. J. and B. Orne, 1848 March
  - Kelsey, C.E. and C.F., 1854 July 10
  - Killingsworth, E. vs. Pearson A. Reading, 1842
  - Kirkham vs. Mayor, et al., 1836
    Building of Girard College-Founder's Hall.
  - Klemm vs. sundry persons, 1828-1830
  - Knight vs. Gavit, 1848 June 27
  - Krauskopf, William vs. James B. Ames, 1846 August 1
  - Kunzi, Abraham, 1835
    Mortgage to John Hallowell
  - Laurence vs. Maule, 1855-1856
  - Leibrick, Conrad, Undated
    Patent.
  - Leiper, Ann G., 1834-1840
    Trust estate material.
  - Leiper, Elizabeth, 1830-1831
    Estate, account with Ash.
  - Leiper, Elizabeth Coultas, 1829 July 17
    Will. See also: Gibbon, James
  - Leiper, George G., William J., Samuel M., 1839 June 6
    Cancelled agreement.
  - Leiper, George G. vs. Bethell, 1831 June
  - Leiper, Mary B., 1853-1858
  - Leiper, Samuel M., 1683-1844
    Brief of Title of Lots.
  - Leiper, Samuel M., 1849-1850
    Concerning monies from Dr. Gray.
  - Leiper, Samuel M., 1852 June 10
    Deed to W.J. Leiper.
  - Leiper, Samuel M., 1852-1857
  - Leiper, Samuel M., 1854 June 5
    Estate exemplification.
  - Leiper, Samuel M., 1855 February 27
    Estate, inventory.
  - Leiper, Samuel M., 1844 December 13
    Estate, report of Master...
  - Leiper, Samuel M., 1855-1857
    Estate vs. W.J. Leiper
  - Leiper, Samuel M., 1852 April 16
    Mortgage.
  - Leiper, Samuel M., 1844
    Searches against.
  - Leiper, Thomas L., 1861 December 30
    Deed to T.L. Kane.
  - Leslie vs. Blitz, Undated
  - Levant (ship), 1849 January 12
  - Levy, Moses, 1825 June 6
    Ground rent lease to George Merritt.
  - Lex, C F, et al, 1849 November 30
    Lease to S.M. Leiper.
  - Lincoln vs. Schooner Volation, 1846 September 21
  - Loftis, Ralph, 1741 December 4
    Mortgage to William Bell.
  - Lombaert vs. Stillwell, 1848 October 16
  - Lombard vs. Bayard, 1847
  - Loran, Stephen, 1833 May 3
  - Lots in Peru, Illinois, 1839 August
  - Lovett vs. Bispham, 1848 July 13
  - Luce, L.J., 1857 February 6
    Deed to A.J. Wilcox.
  - Lukens vs. Cochran, 1833 March 26
  - Lynd, Jr. and Company vs. United States, 1799
  - Magniac, et al vs. Thomson, 1851-1852
  - Maker vs. the Mayor of Philadelphia, 1829-1831
  - Market Street ground rent, 1853 November 15
  - Market Street markets, Undated
    Ordinance relating to the High Street market.
  - Market Street widening, 1830
  - Married Persons Property Act, 1887 June 3
  - Martin vs. Warner, 1848 April 25
  - Martin's Estate, 1831
  - Matcolf, Thomas vs. Capt. Richard Hahn, 1848 December 23
    Libel, wages.
  - Maule, E.R., 1855 February 19
    Deed to Kenneth Jewell.
  - Mayor of Philadelphia vs. Rachel C. Bartram, 1830-1832
  - Mayor of Philadelphia vs. John S. Furey, 1831 June 30
  - Mayor of Philadelphia...release, 1831 March 10
  - Mayor of Philadelphia vs. Executors of J. Wills, 1826 July
  - McAfee vs. the Creole (ship), 1789
  - McCurdy vs. Leiper, 1841 May 12
  - McKean and Elk Land and Improvement Company, 1856 October 18
    Deed to Alonzo J. Wilcox.
  - McNaughten vs. Hannah Tumey, 1847 June 19
  - Mease and Jost vs. the "Clara.", 1861
  - Meeker, et al, 1795 April
    Mortgage to Sharp Delany.
  - Meeker, Samuel, 1806 May 1
    Deed to Anthony Taylor.
  - Merrick, John to John Vaughan, 1837 February 9
  - Merritt, George, 1829 May 26
    Deed to John Davis.
  - Messerves, George, 1827
    For the Franklin Bank.
  - Metcalfe, Joseph and Company, 1840
  - Miller, John J., 1845
    Petition for position in Wyoming County.
  - Mills, Millard S. vs. James E. Craig, 1851
  - Miscellany, 1831-1893
  - Mitchell, A.W., 1847
    Lease to M. Brown.
  - Molony, James, 1770-1836
    Bill of sale to Washington Jackson.
  - Molony, James, 1836
  - Morris, Levi, 1831
    Notes for contract.
  - Morris vs. Nixon, 1836
  - Morris, Thomas vs. Maria Nixon and Henry J. Williams, 1843 July 15
  - Morrison's note, 1872 December
  - Moss vs. Snider, 1842-1844
  - Muhlenberg, Henry Augustus, 1843 October 25
  - Murray, John vs. Donnelly, 1846 August 17
  - Mutual Assurance Company Policy to Washington Jackson, 1833-1834
    See also: Kane, J.K. Settlement with Mutual Assurance Company
  - Myers, et al vs. Brig. Harriet, 1848 June 29
  - Myers vs. Reading, 1840-1841
  - Naglee, Joseph vs. Hannah R. Naglee, 1845 December
  - Newbold, C., 1819
    Release to Silas Weir.
  - Newcastle and Frenchtown Turnpike, Railroad Company vs. Steamer Commodore Stockton, Undated
    Libel.
  - Newlin's Lessee vs. George M. Garwood #1, 1846
  - Newlin's Lessee vs George M. Garwood #2, 1846
  - Notes of controversy with committee of Spring Garden, 1831
  - Notes, Undated
    Regarding slavery.
  - Notes, lists, petition, 1843-1857
  - Nowlen, et al vs. United States, Undated
  - Noyes, Jacob W., 1837 March 30
    Deed to W. L. May.
  - Nugent, 1850 January 17
    Regarding bankruptcy.
  - O'Hara vs. Clay, 1849
  - O'Neill, O'Donnell, O'Kane, 1876, 1885
    Transcription
  - Oliver vs. Weakly, 1853 April 14
  - Osprey (steamship) vs. Barque Delaware, 1850
  - Packer vs. Nixon, 1833 December 26
  - Palmer vs. Peter Crary, 1830
  - Pardons from penitentiary, 1845
  - Parker vs. Culbertson, 1847
  - Parker, Oliver, assignee of Zebulon vs. James S. Hulme, 1849 April
    Parker's patent reaction waterwheel.
  - Parker vs. Nixon, 1853 November 3
  - Parker vs. Perkins, 1849 January
  - Parry, George T., 1860 July
    Agreement with J.N. Horsey.
  - Partridge vs. Patman, 1847 November
  - Patterson, R.M., 1832 December 11
    Estate. Deed to J.K. Kane.
  - Patton vs. Biddle, 1837
  - Peale, Caroline vs. John Hemphill, 1841
  - Peale, Franklin vs. Eliza Greatrake, 1821, 1825
  - Peale, Mrs., 1837
  - Penn, William, 1701 October
    Patent to William Bowlin.
  - Pennsylvania. Attorney general, 1845
  - Pennsylvania. Auditor general, 1845
  - Pennsylvania. Deed, 1796 August 4
    To George Gray signed Thomas Mifflin
  - Pennsylvania vs. Degrange, 1845
  - Pennsylvania vs. Delpit, 1845 October 16
  - Pennsylvania Fire Insurance Company, 1837 November 22
    To R.A. Caldcleugh, on buildings.
  - Pennsylvania vs Johnston, 1845 November 21
  - Pennsylvania vs. Andrew McClean, 1844
  - Pennsylvania vs J. Porter, 1845 June
  - Pennsylvania vs. William Shouse, 1844
  - Pennsyvania vs. Col. J.B. Town, 1845 November
  - Pennsylvania. Treasurer, 1845
  - Pennsylvania vs. Thomas Weaver and Frederick Fritz, 1844 May 20
  - Penrose and Burton vs. Georgiana Peaco, 1849 December
  - Philadelphia. City Commissioners, 1834
    Bills for curbstones..
  - Philadelphia (County), 1846 January 3
    License to Joseph Edel.
  - Philadelphia County vs. Roach, 1845 November 15
  - Philadelphia Mayor vs. James Wills Estate, 1826 July
  - Philadelphia Merchants Exchange, 1831-1832
  - Philadelphia. Orphans Court., 1845 March 1
    Estate of Taylor minors.
  - Philadelphia. Treasurer., 1820 March
  - Pilot's Society vs. Mahoney, 1853
  - Poinsett, Joel R., 1837 April 8
  - Polk, James K., 1844-1846
    Letters dating: 1844 June 8; 1844 June 19; 1844 June 19; 1844 October 4; 1844 October 17; 1846 March 30; 1846 June 11.
  - Pope and Aspinwall, 1839-1840
  - Porter, H.H., 1831-1832
  - Porter vs. Sturgess, 1854 April 6
  - Powell vs ship Champlain, 1847 July 26
  - Prentiss vs. Ellsworth, 1844-1845
    U.S. Commission of patents
  - Prevost, Henry M. vs. Peirson A. Reading, 1842
  - Prichett, T. B. et al, 1837
  - Rakestraw vs. Hammitt, 1825
  - Ravenel-Kohne case, 1853 October 19
  - Rawle, William, 1804
    Opinion.
  - Reed, Jacob and Reed Brothers, 1870-1872
  - Rees, George, 1830 June 8
  - Reid vs. Stanley, 1845 July 8
  - Rensselaer accounts, 1852
  - Rhoads, Philip, 1808 March 11
    Mortgage to David Evans.
  - Richards, Benjamin Wood, 1797-1851
    Notes from Senators and Congressmen.
  - Richards vs. Edwards, 1838 January 21
  - Ridgway vs. Keim, 1850
  - Richards vs. Morris, 1837
  - Richards vs. Ryan, 1841
  - Righter, John, 1850-1852
    Case.
  - Robb, Robert R., 1842
    Affidavit. Concerning a claim upon "Lovell Estate".
  - Roberts, Joseph, 1852 June 14
  - Rockhill vs. Moore, 1844 April 10
  - Rockhill, Thomas, and James Peale, 1849 June 18
    Administrators, etc. to Samuel M. Leiper. Deed for a lot of ground on the west side of Ashton Street and south side of Pine Street.
  - Ross vs. Gibson, 1846 July 6
  - Russell vs. Leiper, et al, 1836
    See Leiper, et al
  - Russell, Robert, 1832
    Estate. Claims...
  - St. John, et al vs. Meade, et al, 1850 May 22
  - Sally Ann (schooner), 1850 October 2
    Protests, etc.
  - Sandy and Beaver Canal Company vs. J. Lippincott, 1836-1837
  - Say, B., 1845
    Heirs.
  - Say, B., 1841
    Property.
  - Say, Benjamin, 1813 March 18
  - Say, Miriam, 1830-1832
  - Say, William P., et al vs. John Ashmead, 1838 September 15
  - Schofield, Lane, 1831
    Controversy.
  - Schuylkill Bank vs. Samuel Moore, 1841
  - Schuylkill meadow land materials, 1760-1764
  - Searches against George Woolley and others, 1848
  - Shelby vs. Bacon, 1814-1818
  - Sheppard, Furman, 1859-1860
    Account with R.P. Kane.
  - Shorthand notes, 1859
  - Sloat and Smith vs. Mercer and Patton, 1846-1852
    Also contains prints of woodworking machinery
  - Sloat vs Plympton, 1846 July 27
  - Small, James H., 1839 May 4
    Testimony...
  - Smith, John J., 1833 December 30
    Deed to John M. Vanharlingen.
  - Smith, John J., 1833 December 30
    Deeds to Thomas C. Cash.
  - Smith, John J. and others, 1835 June 18
    Release. To W. Jackson for right of passageway across his lots lying between Chestnut and George Street and 4th and 5th Streets in the City of Philadelphia.
  - Smith, Samuel, 1843 October 12
    Deed to Thomas Darling.
  - Smith, Samuel, 1847 December
    A fugitive from labour - Wroth claimant.
  - Smith, Stephen, 1845 March 13
    Deeds to E. S. McGlue.
  - Smyth, Frederick, 1785 January 7
    Mortgage to Hugh Roberts.
  - Snider, Jacob, Jr., 1842 October 18
    Lands in Chester County.
  - Snider, Jacob vs. Randall, 1845 November 8
  - Snyder, Enoch vs. William Warrance, Undated
  - Spofford vs. the Pennsylvania and Samson, 1853 May 19
  - Sprague vs. Lane, Undated
  - Stearns vs. Horner, 1848
  - Steel, et al vs. Barge Gen. Cadwalader, Undated
    Powell, et al vs. Barge Maj. Ringgold.
  - Stickney vs. Burke, 1836-1839
  - Stiles vs. Steamboat John Stephens, 1847
  - Stone, James W., 1860
    Claim against the Corn Exchange Insurance Company.
  - Stowe vs. Thomas, 1853 October 26
    Copyright.
  - Strembeck, Jacob, 1829 June 20
    Deed Poll to Washington Jackson
  - Strickland and Struthers vs. Mechanics Bank, 1839 November 29
  - Sunbury and Erie Railroad, 1856
  - Sully, Thomas vs. the St. George Society, 1839 March 22
    Regarding portrait of Queen Victoria.
  - Tabb, John vs. Louisa, 1831
  - Tagg, George, 1849 September 28
    Deed to G. W. Bolivar.
  - Tarr, A.D., 1830
    Insolvent.
  - Taylor, Anthony and Thomas Newbold, 1804 May 1
    Mortgage to Samuel Meeker.
  - Taylor, Henry, 1843 September 1
  - Taylor, John, 1823 November 20
    Act for the relief of ...
  - Taylor, Julia D., 1827 July 25
  - Taylor, Robert, 1848 August 28
    Deed to James L. Taylor.
  - Taylor, Robert vs. Gavitt, et al, 1839
  - Taylor, Robert vs. John Giles, 1832
  - Taylor, Robert vs. the Royal Saxon, 1848 March 24
  - Thomas, Ann G., 1886-1895
  - Thomas vs. Tees, 1832 February 15
  - Thurston, Robert vs. Isaiah Merkle, Joseph Merkle and William Crook, 1854 April 11
  - Titus vs. Conkling, et al, 1849
  - Townsend, Daniel and others vs. Euhaw Baptist Church, 1853 October 10
  - Trivett vs. Jackson, 1836 May 10
  - Truxton, Thomas, 1819
    Deed poll to Silas E. Weir and others.
  - Turbit vs. Dunlevy, 1849 December 10
  - Uhler vs. The Barges, and owners, 1849 February 20
  - United States in relation Jenkins, Crosson and Wynkoop vs. Allen, Sheriff of Philadelphia, 1854 May 3
  - United States vs. Archer's executors, 1843 October
    Ashmead Batz, Volges Betz, Vallyer Boaler Bosseimer, William Brown Brown, Thomas Butler, John Cameron, Nelson Carter Caulsberry, Elijah Clark.
  - United States vs. William Ashmead, 1847 March 11
  - United States vs. Batz and Volges, 1853 January 12
  - United States vs. Betz and Vallyer, 1852 December 13
  - United States vs. Boaler, 1829
  - United States vs. Bosseimer, Undated
  - United States vs. William Brown, 1851
  - United States vs. Thomas Butler, 1851
  - United States vs. John Cameron, 1849 October 2
  - United States vs. Nelson Carter, 1851
  - United States vs. Daniel Caulsberry, 1851
  - United States vs. Elijah Clark, 1851
  - United States vs. Isaiah Clarkson, 1851
  - United States vs. Lewis Clarkson, 1851
  - United States vs. John M. Comegys, 1853 January 29
  - United States vs. Darnard, 1855 May 10
  - United States vs. Darnaud, Undated
  - United States vs. Davis and Gordon, Undated
  - United States vs. Findley, et al, 1840-1843
  - United States vs. Lewis Gales, 1851
  - United States vs. General Taylor (schooner), Undated
  - United States vs. John Goodin, Jr., 1846 September 11
  - United States vs. Henry Green, 1851
  - United States vs. John S. Hanzseke, 1847 December
  - United States vs. John Harding, et al #1, 1846
  - United States vs. John Harding, et al #2
  - United States vs. Hill, 1823
  - United States vs. Hippihappa hats, 1847 March 15
  - United States vs. John Holliday, 1851
  - United States vs. Charles Hunter, 1851
  - United States vs. Randall Hutchinson, 1848 April 15
  - United States vs. John Jackson, 1851
  - United States vs. Washington Jackson, 1839-1840
  - United States vs. Benjamin Johnson, 1851
  - United States vs. Little colored Washerwoman, Undated
    Fugitive, pregnant.
  - United States vs. Marchioness of Abercorn (ship), 1833, 1840
  - United States vs. Wesley McCarren, 1847 May 24
  - United States vs. Jacob Moore, 1851
  - United States vs. John Morgan, 1851 October
  - United States vs. Wilson C. Parks, Charles Williams, Henry M. Kinney, 1850 September 30
  - United States vs. Benjamin Pendergrast, 1851
  - United States vs. Alson Pernsley, 1851
  - United States vs. James Porter alias James May and George Wilson, 1830 April
    Robbery.
  - United States vs. Peter E. Prevall, 1849 November 26
  - United States vs. George Reed, 1851
  - United States vs. The Royal Saxon, 1847 December
  - United States vs. Saunders, Undated
  - United States vs. Silksworth (ship), 1840 June 29
  - United States vs. Henry Sims, 1851
  - United States vs. Sterrett, 1853 February 22
    Pardon.
  - United States vs. William Stetler, 1852 February 17
  - United States vs. Ezekiel Thompson, 1851
  - United States vs. Henry Travis, 1848 September 4
  - United States vs. Williams, 1850 September 18
  - United States vs. George Williams, 1851
  - United States vs. Samuel Williams, 1851
  - United States vs. William Williams, 1851
  - United States vs. George Wilson, 1830
  - United States vs. Collister Wilson, 1851
  - United States vs. William Wood, 1818 June
  - United States vs. Edward D. Yates, 1851 July 14
  - United States Patent Office to Peter Reniers, 1857 April 25
  - Vaidan vs. Isaac Hays, 1844 October 29
  - Vanderslice vs. steamboat Superior, 1849 September
  - Vanharlingen, John M., 1834 October 21
    See also: Smith, John J. Deed to J.M. Vanharlingen.
  - Van Wyck, Isaac vs. P.A. Reading, 1830-1831
  - Vaughan, John, 1842
    Extracts from the last will and testament.
  - Vine Street Wharf, 1830-1831
  - Wagner vs. Wagner, 1835
  - Wakeman vs. Johnston, 1830
  - Wakeman vs Wakeman, 1828
  - Wall and others vs. the Royal Saxon, Undated
  - Walters, Daniel, Undated
  - Washington Mutual Insurance Company vs. the Harriet Parker., 1865 July 7
  - Water Street, 1830 March 18
  - Watson vs. Marks, 1853 May 27
  - Watson vs. Welsh, Undated
  - Watson, Thomas J. vs. Zephyr (steamboat), Undated
  - Webb, et al vs. The Mary Theresa, 1848 July 7
  - Weiner vs. the Arroyo, 1851 June 23
  - Weir, Martha H., 1829 June 20
    Release to Washington Jackson.
  - Wells' accounts and memoranda, 1855
  - Wharfage, 1740 August 18
    Extracts from patents...
  - Wharton, Charles, 1840 October 22
    Mortgage to George Handy.
  - Wharton vs. Leiper, et al, 1831
  - Wheeler, John and Alexander Carothers vs. sloop William McFadden., 1846 September 18
  - Whelan Company, 1840 February
  - Whitney, Reuben M., 1820 March 20
    Mortgage to John Savage.
  - Wilcox, A.J., 1857 August 8
  - Williamson's case, 1855-1858
    Correspondence chiefly to J.K. Kane
  - Williamson vs. Kane, 1855-1857
  - Wilson vs. Barnum, 1849 October 17
  - Wilton vs. Camden and Amboy Railroad, 1845-1848, 1855-1858
  - Woodworth, William, 1829
    Account with J. R. van Rensselaer.
  - Wyeth vs. Blair, 1800 December 29
  - Wynans vs. New York and Maryland Rail Road Company, 1851-1852
  - Wyoming vs. Winchester, 1845 November
  - Young, Snider, vs. Randall, et al., 1845 November 29
  - Young vs. the Penobscot, 1853 March
- Series III. Robert Patterson Kane, 1830-1905; This collection includes letters, letterbooks (1853-1860, legal matters), notebooks on legal cases. Much of this relates to Kane's legal practice in Philadelphia with his father, J. K. Kane, but there is also family correspondence, and much that relates to the Philadelphia Society for the Employment and Instruction of the Poor (1850-1851). One miscellaneous item is the "Recollections" of Joshua Francis Fisher (his life and family).
  Presented by Mrs. Joseph C. Aub, Dr. Oliver Cope, Thomas Pym Cope, and Mrs. Thomas P. Hazard, 1968-1974. Sketchbook donated by Mrs. Oliver Cope and accessioned, 1979 (1979 765.ams).